Master,
take a good look at me.
Since I started following you,
I've gotten so lean...
I don't look like a pig anymore!
What will my species think of me?
Good for you... I think.
See all that fat on you?
If you lost a few pounds,
you'd feel so refreshed.
Look at Wujing.
See how energetic he is!
Master?
Why are they all in pairs in this Mortal world?
Remember, Wujing.
All Dharmas align with life's path,
and life's path is fate.
Follow your fate.
Master,
if fate brings you love one day,
what will you do?
This question...
I might need...
to consult the Scriptures.
Cuilan,
are you doing well today?
Cuilan.
Bajie,
no more distractions.
You should learn from Wukong.
He never has that kind of trouble.
Master,
Big Brother is ignorant.
You can tell by his weapon.
You don't understand?
What do you mean?
He is lacking in love.
Ask his love rod...
What were you talking about?
Say it again.
Big Brother is an expert with his rod...
True to his name,
this handsome Monkey King.
That goes without saying.
You're in a good mood today, Big Brother.
No pants today?
So cool.
They were stolen
in cool air.
If I catch this hateful thief,
I'll rip his pants off
so he's exposed.
Why are you staring at me?
I don't like your pants.
How funny!
Wukong.
Your pants are here.
Master,
if you liked them,
you should have told me.
Whose pants did you say
you would rip off?
Wukong,
I noticed a hole in your pants,
so I sewed them for you.
Try it on.
Lovely.
I like it. Let me try.
Big Brother...
It seems demonic here.
Who are you?
We're just passing through.
If you don't pick on me, I won't pick on you.
But if you do,
I'll hit you.
I'm Marshal Tianpeng.
Give me some respect.
Out of my way.
A local river god.
Did he answer?
What did he say?
Piss off.
There is only one way.
Bro Sha.
Get it through.
Okay.
What an enormous fish!
Master!
Master! Be careful!
Don't worry, Master!
I'm here!
Master!
Wukong!
Big Brother!
I'm all right!
Leave me alone!
Master!
Master,
are you all right?
Totally fine.
We're tired from our journey,
with more dust and dirt on the way.
Please forgive me, Benefactor.
You...
are...
a man?
Well, Benefactor,
do I not look like...
a man?
Who are you?
Your Majesty,
what took you so long?
Next time, we won't be able to conceal it.
Let the maids out.
You're dismissed.
Yes, Madam.
What happened, Your Majesty?
Can you guess...
what I saw earlier today?
What did you see?
Today...
I saw a man.
No way.
How could there be such a toxic creature
in The Womanland?
It's fate.
I even talked to him.
What did he look like?
He has...
eyes that are quite large,
with double eyelids.
His smile...
it's so warm...
and so kind.
Oh, I see.
She is sick.
Her Majesty is sick.
Looks like it's time to open the Ancestral Book.
Of all the poisons, men are the most dangerous.
The first time you meet a man,
if your heart starts to race,
your limbs get weak, and you're trembling all over,
it means you've been cursed
by Man's love poison.
Please, continue.
And then...
Then what?
It's Over.
Over?
You mean there's no cure?
That's the end of the passage.
There's a part missing here.
Is this curse...
contagious?
It only attacks the central nervous system.
It mostly spreads from men to women.
Madam Preceptor,
Ancestor Queen once said,
of all things in this world,
it is man alone
that is most venomous,
and full of deception.
Once you're infected with the love poison,
your heart will break,
and you'll die from sorrow.
The antidote...
is to cut it off at the root.
Men must be killed.
Kill them?
Kill them.
You must be tired today.
Get some rest.
Guards.
Go.
Go look.
Yes, Madam.
Where's Bajie?
Bro Sha.
Master.
Where is Second Brother?
What are you looking at?
Let's bathe together.
Sure!
That's great.
Master.
Help!
Master!
Help me!
Wukong, you mustn't use force.
Amitabha.
Get them.
Look! This is a man.
All women.
They're so scary, Mom.
Benefactor, where am I?
The Womanland of Western Liang.
Hey.
So there aren't...
any males here?
Are you deaf?
The Womanland.
I wonder...
what sin we committed.
Being a man
is a capital crime.
That's truly funny.
What are you looking at?
Her Majesty is here.
The deer.
It's her.
Hey, girl.
Don't you be looking...
at my Master that way.
Did you hear me?
Wukong.
Where are your manners?
Your Majesty.
Yesterday, Our Chief Priest noticed
the Motherhood River was restless.
She knew a poison was coming.
Just as expected.
We caught four poisonous creatures
and a stallion.
Please be sensible in your decision,
and pay no attention to their mistaken ideas.
Your Majesty,
my party just came here by mistake.
We are not poisonous.
Don't quibble!
The evidence is here.
Give us an explanation
after you see it.
Our Ancestor predicted...
there would be a monk
leading a monkey,
a pig,
and this blue-skinned bruiser here.
Their arrival will lead to
the end of The Womanland.
We have a picture to prove it.
Oh my gosh.
It looks exactly the same.
Look.
Just look...
My portrait is so lifelike.
Obviously, it's a bat.
So that's... a bat-pig?
That can't be a monkey.
It's a cockroach, obviously.
A cockroach-monkey.
Wukong...
Some new species?
Stop it! Now!
Get them for execution.
Yes, Madam.
Wait!
Hold on.
Her Majesty means...
she has to question them in person...
before she kills them.
Take them away.
Master,
if you agree,
I can talk with them alone.
Master,
on your command,
I'll break out
and smash everything.
Big Brother,
I'm sure Master won't agree.
Wukong,
what are you waiting for?
Break it now.
Your Majesty, you've come at this late hour...
You just want to see him, right?
Yeah.
No.
I just want to figure out
what this poison nonsense is about
before Madam Preceptor kills them.
Now.
Show me your morale.
Imposing.
Let's go!
Go!
Master...
just go.
Rise!
Master.
Are you okay?
Slowly.
Bajie.
Give me a hand.
Master,
it looks like someone...
set an enchanted barrier here.
As expected. We can't get out.
So, what should we do?
Let's go back
and ask that girl.
I know where Her Majesty is.
Wujing.
Are we walking back?
Master,
Her Majesty is here.
Who did it?
It's too cruel.
Cut it out!
We were attacked.
Who did it?
It must be them.
Everyone.
It's time to test our means.
If you've got anything good,
show it now.
We must find our way out.
Wukong.
What good
do you think I've got?
Master.
You have nothing good.
We...
were just attacked.
So...
you did it?
We didn't do it.
I need to question you in person.
What are you staring at?
Yeah, I'm staring at you. So?
Your Master told you not to.
You dare hit me?
I dare you to stare again.
Well, I'm staring again. Now what?
Your Master told you not to.
Do you dare to hit me?
Are you acting fierce?
I don't like old men.
Don't bother.
I'm not interested in you.
We're too different, you and me.
What's different now?
If you lose, you have to tell the truth.
Bring it on!
Did I win?
Hold on!
Do it again.
Lost again.
I let Master down.
I let Big Brother down.
Look how macho you are!
You...
are...
far more macho.
I don't fear death. Why should I fear you?
Then drop dead right now.
You drop dead first.
Okay.
How uppity!
Ancestor Queen once said,
among all things in this world,
men are the most venomous,
and full of deception.
First, he tempts her with lies,
Then, he makes her have his babies.
After the babies are born, he'll ignore her.
And finally, he'll find another woman to trap.
Is that so?
Amitabha.
Your Majesty.
Actually, I...
I'm quite different from
the kind of man you described.
That's it.
Madam Preceptor told us
this is the very lie every man tells.
Now I see...
you're just like every other man.
If you don't trust me, Your Majesty,
why bother coming to me?
Because...
because I miss you.
But they say it's a disease.
It must be cured.
Your Majesty,
have you...
taken your medicine?
It's love poison.
Incurable.
So...
are you poisoned?
Do you miss me?
Your Majesty,
I'm not that good a man.
Not for you.
I'm a monk.
There are many things... I can't do.
Plus, I have many Rules
and Commandments to observe.
Like what?
For example...
I'm a strict vegetarian.
So am I.
I always get up early.
I don't sleep in, either.
I'm not a ladies' man.
Neither am I.
Your Majesty.
Please. Let us go.
Show us the way out.
Let us travel to the West.
Do you hate me?
No. I don't hate you.
I only have one goal
for this life of mine...
to travel West, find the Scriptures,
and return to the world to ease its suffering.
This travel log...
will record my thoughts
and insights along the way.
You'll understand after you read it.
Keep it safe.
I don't have a copy.
You can return it when you're done.
You won't need to.
Just... give it to her.
Be generous.
Wukong.
When did you come in?
Well, I...
I came in as you were talking about veggies.
Since you accepted his gift,
tell us,
where is the way out?
I have no idea where it is.
Our tribe has never attempted
to leave The Womanland.
Give it back.
But I'll do anything I can
to help you find a way out.
The Preceptor is here.
Madam Preceptor.
I've questioned them.
Your Majesty,
did you fall for him?
No.
Why would I?
All right, then.
So let me just...
kill them all tomorrow.
Are you fine with that?
Yes, I am.
These toxic creatures should die.
Fine.
That's fine.
Wukong.
That's the thing about women.
Ancestor Queen,
where's Her Majesty?
Her Majesty thought it would be...
too cruel to watch.
Oh.
I've changed the arrows for execution.
Play dead before it's over.
Meet me at the foot of Mount Saintess later.
I have a plan.
This time...
will we be all right?
Execute them!
Wujing!
Master.
Die quickly.
How should I die?
He really knows the trick.
What a vivid death!
Watch and learn.
Master!
Master...
Awesome.
Come on.
Wait.
Guards, change the arrows...
for more powerful ones.
Why the change?
Being a man is a capital crime.
And being an ugly one...
double guilty!
Don't you have any taste?
I just have nice skin, okay?
Shoot!
I protest!
I'm done.
Throw them off the cliff!
Yes, Madam.
Keep quiet.
Master.
Wukong.
Bajie.
He's all right.
This is the Motherhood River.
It's where The Womanland began.
Motherhood River.
Long, long ago,
our Ancestor...
our Ancestor was betrayed.
An unfaithful Man, on their wedding day.
What's more,
that... man...
even tried to kill her.
And so...
when she chose to come here,
set the enchanted barrier,
and hide in seclusion,
I remember now.
Afterwards,
she recorded her lifetime
her experiences, back in the outside world
into the Ancestral Book in the Royal Library.
But the Book has a fragment missing.
That's likely the page
leading the way out of The Womanland.
That is to say...
your Ancestor
told the little crawfishes...
to guard this place.
Put another way,
this missing part
is probably...
hidden somewhere around here.
So what shall we do?
Wukong!
Find it soon!
It should be the face of your Ancestor
here on this sculpture, right?
Yes.
This is her sacred land.
No admittance.
So, you're safe here.
Absolutely.
Wukong.
Look.
The missing part, you said...
is it like that?
That's it.
Get it.
Grasp it.
I gotta hide.
I gotta go.
So tired.
It hurts.
Come on.
You won't make it.
Lots of people.
I gotta hide.
I gotta fly.
Please tell me
the way out.
Damned monkey.
Monkey!
Hey, big guy,
beat him up!
Big Brother, let me help.
Big trouble!
I'll run!
Your Majesty,
Golden Cudgel!
Big trouble!
I've gotta get outta here.
Master!
Move!
Have you found it?
No.
Missed.
Gotta dodge!
Come on!
I gotta run!
So... tired...
Come on out!
Shoot me...
if you can.
Your Majesty.
Didn't...
get me.
Missed...
again.
Oh...
I dodged it.
Dodged...
I'll run!
I'm okay.
Help me! I quit!
I quit!
It hurts...
Don't come over,
or I'll tear it apart.
It hurts! That's my meat.
Don't do it.
Please! No!
I quit.
Don't tear me apart.
You got my body,
but you won't get my...
my words!
Master!
Rise!
Don't do this to me.
I'm wrong.
Let me go.
Damned kid.
How dare you compete with me!
Don't play with fire!
Master.
The words.
It reads...
that the gate only opens
once you've learned what love is.
So what is love?
Well...
it's something...
I don't know much about.
But once...
I heard a rumor.
A romance.
Here in The Womanland.
A girl who fell in love...
with a river.
But they'd never met.
What's it like, outside The Womanland?
If... if it's possible,
I'd like to go out, just to have a look.
I wonder...
If I met the first person on the outside,
what would that look like?
If anyone can hear me,
could you answer me?
Who are you?
Why can't I see you?
But it seems like I can feel...
what's in your mind.
I believe that
you should be able to feel me, as well.
If...
If I come here for you every day,
will you always be here?
One can't find the way out of the nation,
and the other can't find the way in.
But the River stayed for her.
It stayed for this girl,
and stopped flowing.
Still ever since.
Ouch!
My belly hurts.
Ow!
Master, what's wrong?
Help, Bro Monkey.
What happened to you?
Oh, I see.
They fell in the river
and drank the water from it.
What's wrong with the water?
The water of the Motherhood River
can get you pregnant.
Congratulations.
So, you're all pregnant.
Wukong.
I'm pregnant.
I can't believe it!
I'm going to be a mother.
Serves you right.
What do we do?
We must get out of here.
Haven't found the way out yet.
And you three are pregnant.
Why were you so careless?
What do we do?
Big Brother.
Now it's us, not you,
and we're pregnant.
It's okay.
Indeed.
Wukong.
Do something.
Master...
Take a look. Do I look...
Like I've had a baby?
Actually,
there's still a way.
Miscarriage Cave
Monkey.
Hurry.
Your Master and Brothers
will give birth in three days.
Time waits for no one.
Don't worry,
I'll be right back.
Mandarin ducks and butterflies,
With a charming garden in Spring.
Tell me, Holy Priest,
Am I beautiful?
Great Sage.
The As-You-Will Immortal?
Are you scared?
A man?
You are a man.
You watch your mouth.
They say I'm the most beautiful woman
in the country.
Bother!
My Master is pregnant.
I need to find water
from the Miscarriage Spring,
do you have any?
Okay,
just a minute.
Am I beautiful?
We have the Yin Spring and Yang Spring here.
So I have to blend the Yin with the Yang
and then the Yang with the Yin,
alternating seven or eight times.
After that, I'll add in goji, jujube,
scallions, garlic...
up to 49 precious herbs,
extracting their essence for 81 days.
Then you'll have the water
from Miscarriage Spring...
for one man.
Eighty-one days?
Yes.
It won't do.
Anything faster?
Sure!
Then I'll do it faster,
blending the Yin with the Yang,
then the Yang with the Yin,
and go 7 or 8 times more quickly
so that I can get the essence 81 days sooner.
Do you have any in stock?
Sure!
You mean it?
Look.
But... it's gone now.
How frustrating!
I know it's a painstaking process.
And yet, in that moment...
holding your child in your arms...
I think you'll find
that all the pains
will be worth it.
Your Majesty, do you mean
you want me to give birth
to this baby?
If you want to save the world,
how can you abandon this baby?
Every new life
is equally precious.
Master!
I'm so desperate!
Wujing.
What's wrong?
I lost my whole beard.
But you look good, right?
Yes.
But I'm extremely anxious now.
I'm so troubled.
I keep either eating or sleeping
just like a pig.
Who are you picking on?
Shut up!
Master.
Don't pressure an expectant mother.
Don't touch me.
I don't want to live anymore.
The truth is,
the Miscarriage Spring can't end a pregnancy.
The real Miscarriage Spring is in my eyes.
You need to touch me with true feelings,
and make me shed tears with true feelings.
That's the Spring you want.
Great Sage.
Touch me.
Touched.
To touch.
Not to hurt.
It's my heart.
You need to touch my heart, Great Sage.
True feelings.
With true feelings, bro.
Tears from beatings don't count.
What are true feelings?
When a man
is with a woman,
the true feeling is love.
Idiot.
All of a sudden,
I'm feeling happy.
I'm so happy.
Oh no.
Baby Tang.
Baby Tang has no heartbeats.
She just kicked me a while ago.
It's okay.
She is just asleep.
Close your eyes.
Feel her heartbeats.
Give birth to her.
I'll raise her for you.
If I'm to raise her,
no matter how hard it is,
it's my duty.
Great Sage,
why are you going to the West?
To get the Scriptures, and enlighten...
all sentient beings.
All sentient beings?
You are so great.
But all these
abortive infants were also
among the sentient beings, aren't they?
Every time they aborted
I would light a candle here
to light up the way for those infants.
If they don't get rid of the babies,
how can we get to the West?
Whatever.
I'll be the bad guy...
this time.
As long as Master makes it to the West,
no matter how extreme the situation is,
I can only say:
Come on!
Let go.
Stay still.
I'm almost crying.
Great Sage.
Please tell your Master
I truly envy him
for having you.
Why are you so cool?
Master.
I got the water from Miscarriage Spring.
The water of Miscarriage Spring.
Wukong.
I've made a big decision.
I've decided...
I'm going to have this baby.
You thought it over?
Go ahead, then.
Oh yeah! We'll have babies.
Let's celebrate.
Freeze!
Master.
My duty is to protect you.
You're no ordinary.
Hindered by a child,
how can you proceed
and how shall I protect you?
Unfreeze.
It's gone.
Why did you decide it for him?
That's his child.
You don't understand my Master better than I do.
What if he wants more
than your understanding?
I'll tell you this...
in my Master's heart,
getting those Scriptures... it's everything.
There's no room for anything else.
It's not my remark.
If you don't believe it,
just ask Buddha.
When I was young,
the Temple Abbot told me
to copy the Scriptures
when I was upset.
As I improved my handwriting,
my mind would be calmed.
Don't worry.
I'm all right.
How can I want it both ways?
To have you and Buddha on the same page?
Human sensuality weakens my soul.
Forget it, then. That's how it goes.
Here I am, destined for the West.
Why must I meet you now?
How can I forget you?
I'd rather forget my own name.
Forget my reign, my fortune.
Ignore your Rules and Commandments.
If you love me, hold on to me.
Take me on your journey.
Say no more merciful things.
Waste no time and stop waiting.
Even if I'll vanish in next life,
I must be with you in this life.
How can I want it both ways?
To have you and Buddha on the same page?
Human sensuality weakens my soul.
Forget it, then. That's how it goes.
Here I am, destined for the West.
Why must I meet you now?
How can I forget you?
I'd rather forget my own name.
Forget my reign, my fortune.
Ignore your Rules and Commandments.
Break them apart.
Take this evil monk away.
Madam Preceptor.
He's not like what you think.
Your Majesty, I just don't want you to
betray the will of our Ancestors
and persist in your mistakes.
But...
what if Ancestor was mistaken
from the very beginning?
Then we are part of her mistake.
And forever we will be.
Don't worry, Your Majesty.
I can assure you that
I'm just putting him in jail for now.
I won't inflict a wound on him.
Everything I've done
is only for you.
No worries, Your Majesty.
I will be all right.
Aren't we going to the jail?
Your Excellency.
Cast him out.
Where are you taking me?
Move!
Push him out!
Your Majesty.
No!
In the hall...
that day,
when I submitted Ancestor's predictions...
there was a passage
I didn't read.
It said,
one day,
Her Majesty
would leave The Womanland.
No way.
Heaven chooses Her Majesty.
She bears the bloodline of The Womanland.
If she leaves,
everything here will be bleak and desolate.
The Womanland...
will no longer exist.
Big Brother.
Sun Wukong.
You're a man of miracles.
Please save Her Majesty.
Where's my Master?
He's now sailing
with Her Majesty
on the Sea of Suffering.
The Sea of Sufferings?
The Sea is boundless
with no way back.
Once you set off,
you'll drift for a lifetime.
No one's ever made it out alive.
I'm sure
to send you back ashore, Your Majesty.
Master!
Her Majesty...
I need a sip of water.
It tastes bitter.
It'll only make you thirstier.
My flesh...
can make a mortal immortal.
If you don't mind,
you can have a bite.
What is it like...
outside The Womanland?
There's also...
a sea of suffering out there.
But on that sea,
everyone is an island.
Everyone...
is on the drift.
But when does their drift end?
If I can find the Scriptures,
I'm bound to lead them ashore.
However,
beyond the suffering,
there is also joy.
It's a pity...
I wish I were able
to show you around, here in this life.
It doesn't matter.
In the next life, then.
Sure.
In the next life.
What a surprise!
The gate...
it's right at the end of the Sea of Suffering.
The gate is open.
What is love, then?
I'm going with you.
What about The Womanland?
I'll abandon my reign, give up my fortune.
You can observe your Rules and Commandments.
Master!
Rise!
Wukong.
Master!
Are you all right?
Master.
Let's go!
Let's go.
Master.
Are you really taking her along?
This child...
bears the bloodline of The Womanland.
You are Preceptor to the nation now.
The only mission in your life
is to raise her well.
Don't fail the will of Heaven, now.
Are you here?
Today...
is my last time.
I won't be back.
Because from today,
I have accepted my mission.
I'll spend my entire life
protecting this child.
She will be...
Queen of The Womanland.
While we wait to begin,
as it turns out,
it's all come to an end.
Mercy Goddess.
Dear Ancestor,
Our people in The Womanland
will cut off our hair,
and weave it into an Everlight Lamp.
We beg of you...
our Ancestor...
please save Her Majesty.
The Everlight Lamp
must burn to the end.
Only then
will Her Majesty have the chance to wake up.
Xuanzang,
in this world,
you can only let go
of the things you've never owned.
Will you choose
to love one person,
or all of humanity?
Remember,
the day you put your cassock on again,
is the day you resume
your journey to the West.
Keep it in mind.
Do you miss me?
Mercy Goddess.
Get attached!
Freeze!
Wukong.
Let's just take the cassock along.
Over time,
perhaps this romance
will fade away.
By that time,
you have to be able to wear this cassock again.
If time were the best medicine,
there wouldn't be so much
incurable suffering and reluctant partings
in this world.
Why are you still here?
You're finally awake.
I had a dream.
You've waited twenty years for me.
It's out.
The Everlight Lamp is out.
Her Majesty is probably awake.
Go see Her Majesty.
No, no.
I can't.
Everything has its destiny.
Go greet the sea.
No.
No!
Master!
Your Majesty.
Madam Preceptor.
Your Majesty, are you all right?
My child.
I'll never leave my Queen.
Please... just go.
Master!
Master.
Go!
Rise!
Buddha,
They're drowning in the Sea of Suffering.
Please advise me...
how to offer them salvation.
God of the River Oblivion,
for the past twenty years,
you've been obsessed.
And now you've committed a tremendous sin.
Do you know you're at fault?
River God...
repent and be saved.
I had a dream.
I dreamed that...
your hair was long,
and we grew old together.
But you...
you weren't happy.
God of the River Oblivion,
I understand the root of your inner pain.
In fact,
the gate is always there...
but it's our hesitation, our unwillingness
that keeps us from going through it.
Love is the reason
we are born into this world,
then born again, through endless reincarnations.
But fully understanding the wonders of love...
is eternal.
From this love, I've learned that
love for a person, or love for the world,
it's the same.
I will recite the Sutras for you,
thousands of times a day,
until I reach the Thunder Monastery.
There, I will enshrine you over the pulpit,
forever illuminated by Buddha,
to help find your justice
and proper retribution.
How can I want it both ways?
To have you and Buddha on the same page?
Human sensuality weakens my soul.
Forget it, then. That's how it goes.
Here I am, destined for the West.
Why must I meet you now?
How can I forget you?
I'd rather forget my own name.
Forget my reign, my fortune.
Ignore your Rules and Commandments.
See you.
No.
We won't meet again.
Perhaps in the next life.
Even if it means I won't have a next life,
I must be with you in this one.
Disciples.
What is that place ahead?
They're mountains.
One after another.
Got a name?
The Fiery Mountains.
My goodness.
That sounds... hot.
Let's go!
Hey, stop. We're here.
I'm sorry.
Where's Big Brother and Second Brother?
They left first.
Wanted me to tell you goodbye.
No way! Why? They're so mean.
Second Brother asked me
to read these words...
just for you.
With feeling.
Deep feelings, and true.
Sister,
forgive me for sneaking out so quietly.
I haven't achieved what I wanted yet.
I need this journey to the West.
Don't wait for me.
Please remember
my handsome good looks.
But, I ask you...
forget about the rest of me.
Please.
Actually,
I prefer your original look.
You mean this one?
She's not talking about you.
She's talking about Second Brother.
Actually, your blue-skinned look
is pretty cute, too.
But what'll you do with this outfit?
If I tell you,
don't get scared off.
I'm the Curtain-Lifting General.
The Curtain-Lifting General?
What's that?
You don't know about this?
In Heaven, when the Jade Emperor passes by,
I'll lift the curtain for him.
Lift the curtain.
You're so talented.
Isn't that a watchman's job?
That's an important post!
Yeah . It sure is.
You are so cool.
We won't meet again.